[Music]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se-
radio.net SC radio is brought to you by
the it computer society and by It
software Magazine online at computer.org
[Music]
software if slow QA processes bottleneck
you or your software engineering team
and you're releasing slower because of
it you need to check out QA wolf.com QA
wolf gets engineering teams to 80% %
automated end-to-end test coverage and
helps them ship two times faster by
reducing QA Cycles from hours to minutes
with over fstar reviews on G2 and
customer testimonials from salesloft
Strata AutoTrader and many more you're
in good hands go to QA wolf.com to see
if they can help you squash the QA
bottleneck hi everyone I'm Priyanka
Ragin for software engineering radio and
today I'm chatting with Stevie Caldwell
a senior engineering Tech lead at
Fairway
she has a lot of experience in research
development architecture design audits
as well as client support and incident
analysis to Top This Stevie has a wealth
of knowledge in areas of devops
kubernetes and Cloud
infrastructure today we're going to be
talking about zero trust Network
architecture specifically diving deep
into a reference architecture for
kubernetes welcome to the show Stevie
thank you thank you for having me it's
great to be here and I'm pit to talk to
you today so the first question I wanted
to ask you is trust and security are the
core of computing and so in this regard
would you be able to explain to us or
Define the term zero trust Network
architecture yeah it's often useful to
Define it in terms of what was or what
might be even still standard now which
is a more uh perimeter-based approach to
security also has been called Castle
approach people have talked about castle
and
and essentially it's that you're
trusting anything you're you're setting
up a perimeter of security that says
anything outside my cluster or outside
my network is to be uh looked upon with
skepticism is not to be trusted and
anything that but once you're inside the
network you're cool just sort of
defining using the network itself as the
identity versus um with zero trust the
challenge is that trust no one it's like
the x file
so you want to treat even things that
are inside your perimeter inside your
network with skepticism with care you
want to remove that implicit trust and
make it explicit so that you're being
meaningful and deliberate about what
things you allow to communicate with
each other inside your network I like to
use an analogy one that I I think I like
a lot is like an apartment building
where you have an apartment building you
have a front door that faces the public
that people are given a key to if they
live in that building so they get a key
so that they're allowed to enter that
building once they're inside the
building you don't just leave all the
apartment doors open still right you
don't just allow people and assume well
you're in the building now so you can go
wherever you want you still have like
Network you still have uh security at
each of like the apartments because
those are locked so I like to think
about the zero trust sort of working
that that same way that's great so one
of the books I was reading before you
know preparing for this show was the
zero trust networks book we had the
authors of that book on the show about
four years back and they talked about
you know some fundamental principles of
zero trust I think pretty much similar
to what you're talking about like the
concept of trusting no one depending a
lot on
segmentation following principles of
lease Privileges and then of course
monitoring is there something that you
can elaborate a little bit about
yeah so um there is this framework
around zero trust where there are these
pillars that sort of group the domains
that you would commonly want to secure
in a zero trust implementation so um
it's identity which deals with like your
users so you know who's accessing your
system what are they allowed to access
even down to like physical access from a
user like can you swipe into a data
center there's application work
workloads which deals with making sure
that your you know your applications and
workloads are also Vigilant about who
they talk to you know an example of this
is like workload security inside a
kubernetes cluster right so making sure
that only the applications that need
access to a resource have that access
not letting everything right to an S3
bucket for example there's network
security which is where a lot of people
focus honestly when you start thinking
about zero trust that's micro uh
segmentation that's isolating your
sensitive resources on the network it's
moving away from that perimeter only
approach to network security there's
data security so isolating your
sensitive data encryption you know in
transit and at rest there's device
security which is about your devices
your laptops your phones and then across
all those are three additional sort of
they're sort of pillars but they're kind
of crosscutting because there's the
observability and monitoring piece where
you want to be able to see that all
these things in action you want to be
able to log uh user access to something
or you know Network traffic there's
Automation and orchestration so that
you're actually taking some of the human
error element out of your network out of
your you know zero trust security
solution and then there's a governance
piece where you want to have policy IES
in place that people follow and that
systems follow and they have have ways
of enforcing those policies as well okay
that's great so the next question I
wanted to ask you is about this term
reference architecture which is used
there seems to be multiple approaches
could you explain the term and then your
thoughts on these multiple
approaches yeah uh so reference
architecture is a template is a way to
draw out uh solutions to solve a
particular problem it makes it easier to
implement Your solution provides a
consistent solution across different
domains so you're not Reinventing the
wheel right so if this app team needs to
do a thing if you have a reference
architecture that's already been built
up they have the ability to just look at
that and Implement what's there versus
going out and starting from scratch it's
interesting because I said I'm a
Rockstar and I'm not obviously but I do
make music in my own time and one of the
things that's important
when you're like mixing a track is using
a reference track and it's sort of the
same it's sort of the same idea when I
was reading about this I was like oh
this this feels very familiar to me
because it's the same idea it's
something that someone else has already
done that you can follow along with to
implement your own thing without having
to start all over again and they can be
as they can be very detailed or they can
be high level really depends on the
domain that you're trying to solve for
but at the basics it should probably
contain at least like information about
what you're what you're solving and then
what the purpose of the design is so
that people are able to more readily
determine if it's useful to them or not
that's great and um I think the other
question I wanted to ask which I think
you alluded to in the first answer when
I asked you about zero trust Network
architectures why should we care about a
zero trust reference architecture in the
cloud basically for cloud native
Solutions why is this
important I think it's very much because
in the cloud you don't have the same
level of control that you have outside
the cloud right so if you're running
your own data center you control the
hardware the servers that it runs on you
control the networking equipment to some
degree you're able to set up you know
the access to the cage to the data
center you just have more oversight and
and insight into what's happening in
fact but you don't own the things in the
cloud there's more sprawl there's no
physical boundaries your workloads can
be spread across multiple regions
multiple clouds it's harder to know
who's accessing your apps and data how
they're accessing it and when you try to
secure all these different aspects you
can often come up with like a kind of
hodge podge of solutions that become
really difficult to manage and and the
more complex and difficult to manage
your Solutions are the easier it is for
them to like not work not be configured
correctly and then expose you to risk so
it's a unified means of controlling
access within the
domain and zero trust is a good way to
do that in a cloud environment I think
that that makes a lot of sense right now
the the way you've answered it so you're
running workloads on a on an
infrastructure where you have no control
over so as a result it really makes some
sense that you implement this zero trust
reference
architecture yeah so uh just to kind of
ask you at a very high level before we
dive deep is what are the main
components of uh uh zero trust Network
architecture for kubernetes is that
something that you can detail for us uh
so for kubernetes cluster I would say
some of the main reference some of the
main points you'd want to hit in
reference architecture would be Ingress
so um how the traffic is getting into
your cluster what's allowed in where
it's allowed to go once it's in the
cluster so you know what services your
Ingress is allowed to forward traffic to
and then maintaining uh identity and
security so encryption and
authenticating the identity of the the
parts that are taking place in your
workload communication using something
like uh certain manager certainly other
Solutions as well but that is a that's a
piece that I feel like should be
addressed in your reference architecture
uh the service mesh piece so you know
that is what is most commonly used for
securing Communications between
workloads so for doing that encryption
in transit and for um verifying the
identities of those components and just
defining what internal components can
talk to each other and then beyond that
what components can access what
resources that might actually live
outside your clusters so what components
are allowed to access your RDS databases
your S3 buckets what components are
allowed to talk across your VPC to
something else like it can get pretty
large which is why it's important to I
think split them up into domains right
so but with a kubernetes cluster I think
those are your main things Ingress
workload
communication encryption data security
okay so I think it a good segue to get
into like the details right now
so when we did this episode on zero
trust networks the uh guest there one of
the approaches um that he suggested on
starting was trying to figure out what
your most important assets are and then
start going outwards instead of like you
know trying to First protect the
perimeter and going you know the inward
approach he said start with your assets
and then start gr outwards which I found
very interesting when I was listening to
that that episode and I just thought
I'll ask you about your thoughts on that
before diving deep into the pillars that
we just
discussed yeah I think that that makes
total sense I think starting with the
most critical data defining your attack
surface helps you to focus efforts not
get overwhelmed trying to implement zero
trust everywhere at once because that's
the recipe for complexity and again as
we said complexity can lead to miscon
configured systems so you know determine
what your sensitive data is what are
your critical applications and start
there I think that's um it's a good way
to go about it okay so I think we can
probably now go into like the different
concepts and the book that I was looking
at was the zero trust reference
architecture for communities uh which
you pointed me to which had talked about
these four open source projects one is
the Emissary Ingress linkerd uh CT
manager and Polaris so I thought we
could start with say uh the first part
which is the Emissary engress because we
talked a lot about what comes into the
network but before I go into that is
there something that when you start
doing this different thing is there one
something that we need to do in terms of
the environment do we need to bootstrap
it so that all of these different
components trust each other in the zero
trust is there something that ties this
all together if you're installing these
different components in your in your
cluster in general if you install
Everything at Once the sort of default I
think is to allow everything so there is
no implicit deny in effect so you can
install Emissary Ingress and set up your
your host and your you know your
mappings and get traffic from Ingress
into your to your services without
having to set anything up the thing that
will determine
that trust is going to be the service
mesh which is Linker D in our service in
in our reference architecture and Linker
d by default will not deny traffic so
you can inject that sidecar proxy that
it uses which we'll I'm sure talk about
later into any workload and it won't
cause any any any problems it's not a
Deni by default so you have to
explicitly go in and start putting in
these parameters that will restrict
traffic but I was wondering in terms of
like like each of these separate
components is there anything that we
need to you know sort of like bootstrap
the environment before we start is there
anything else that we should keep track
of or do we just sort of install each of
these components which which we let me
talk about and then like how do they
trust each other well they trust each
other automatically because that's sort
of the default in a cluster yeah okay so
you install everything and uh kubernetes
by default does not have a ton of much
security um right out of the box so you
install those things they talk to each
other okay so then let's just then Deep
dive into each of these components so
what is Emissary Ingress and how does it
tie in with the zero trust principles
that we just talked about uh you know
which is monitoring your traffic which
is coming into your network how should
one think about the perimeter
and encryption and things like that so I
hope I do if anyone from imary or from
Ambassador hears this I hope I do your
product um justice so imary Ingress
first of all is a it's um it's an
Ingress it's an alternative to using the
built-in Ingress objects that are
already enabled in the kinetes API and
one of the cool things about uh Emissary
is that it decouples the aspects of
north south routing so you can lock down
access to those things individually
which is nice because when you don't
have those things decoupled when it's
just one object that anyone in the
cluster with access to the object can
configure then it makes it pretty easy
for someone to mistakenly expose
something in a way they didn't want to
or to you know introduce some sort of
security issue or
vulnerability so in terms of what to
think about with Ingress when you're
talking about perimeter I think the
basic things are determining what you
want to do with encryption so you know
traffic comes into your cluster are
folks allowed to enter your cluster
using unencrypted traffic or do you want
to force redirection to encryption is
the request coming from a client like do
you have some sort of workload or
service that you need to authenticate
against in order to be able to use it
and if it is coming from a client like
figuring out how to determine whether or
not to accept it so you can use
authentication uh to determine if that
request is coming from an allowed Source
you can rate limit to help mitigate
potential abuse another question you
want might want to set up is just
generally should you are there are there
requests that you just should not allow
you know so are there IPS paths or or
something that you want to drop and and
don't want to allow into the cluster at
all or maybe they're private um so they
exist but you don't want people to be
able to to hit them those are the kind
of things you should think about when
you're looking at configuring your
perimeter specifically via like a
Emissary Ingress or some other
Ingress okay I think the other thing is
uh how do you define host names and
secure it I'm assuming as an attacker
this would be one thing that they're
constantly looking for so can you just
talk a little bit about how that's done
with emistry in R so if I understand the
question so Emissary Ingress uses there
are a number of crds that get installed
in your cluster that allow you to define
the various pieces of imary Ang grass
and one of those is a host object and
within the host object you defined the
the host names that Emissary is going to
listen on so that will be accessible
from outside your network and I was
talking about the decoupled nature so
the host is its own separate object as
opposed to Ingress which puts the host
in the Ingress object that sits
alongside your actual workload in that
Nam space so the host object itself can
be locked down in in terms of
configuring it can be locked down in uh
using arbac so that only certain people
can access it can edit it can configure
it which is already already creates like
a a nice layer of security there just
being able to restrict who has the
ability to change that that object and
then and then your devs will create
their mapping resources that attach to
that host and allow that traffic to go
back to the back end and then other than
that you're
also going to create well you should
create a TLS CT that you're going to
attach to your uh Ingress and that's
going to terminate TLS there so that
encryption piece is another way of like
securing your host I guess okay I I
guess the so this is the part where you
when you have the uh certificate of
course that takes care of your
authentication bit as well right all the
incoming requests it takes care well on
the incoming request to the cluster no
because that's the standard TLS stuff
where it's just unidirectional right so
unless the client has set up Mutual TLS
which generally they do not then it's
just a matter of verifying the identity
of the the host itself to the client the
host doesn't have any verification
okay so I think now that we're talking a
little bit about certificates I think
it's a good time to talk a little bit
about the other aspect which is the CT
manager so this is used to manage uh the
trust in our reference architecture so
can you talk a little bit about the C
manager with maybe some information on
all the parties involved so C manager is
it's a solution that generate
certificates for you so C manager works
with ISS ERS so that are external to
your cluster although you can also do
self-signed but uh you wouldn't really
want to do that in production and so it
works with uh these external issuers and
essentially handles a life cycle of
certificates in your cluster so it using
uh shims you can request certificates
for your workloads and rotate them or
renew them rather I think the default is
the certificates are valid for 90 days
and then 30 days before they expire
certificate manager will attempt to
renew it for you and so that enables
your standard north south security via
Ingress and then it also can be used in
conjunction with Linker D to help
provide the glue uh between the East
West security with the the Linker D
Sears by I believe uh it's used to
provision the trust anchor
itself that Linker uses for signing yeah
I guess yeah I think that makes uh I
think the right now this uh we need to
also secure the East West as much as the
north south yeah that's the purpose of
the the service meshes for that East
West TLS uh uh configuration yeah okay
so you talked a little bit about also
the certificate a life cycle right in
the CT manager and that one is a it's a
massive pain for uh people who are
managing certificates uh can you talk a
little bit about how do you automate
trust is that something that's also
provided out of the box
so there is SE manager does have I think
another another component that's called
the trust manager I'm not as familiar
with that I think that is and I think
that comes into play
specifically with being able to rotate
the caert that Linker D installs so it's
getting a little bit into like the
Linker D architecture but at its core I
think Linker D when you install it it
has its own inter internal CA and you
can essentially use CER manager and you
can use cert manager and the trust
manager to manage that ca for you so
that you don't have to manually create
those key Pairs and and save those off
somewhere C manager takes care of that
for you and when your ca is uh due to
need to be rotated C manager via the
trust manager I think takes care of that
for you okay okay i i l a a note to the
reference architecture so that's perhaps
the listeners could actually dive deep
into that but the question I wanted to
ask is also in terms of these these
trusted authorities so these must be the
same are there any like trusted
authorities can you talk about that in
the SE manager is that something that do
we have typical issuers that the SE
manager communicates with yeah there's
so there's a long list actually that you
can look at on the SE manager website
some of the common ones are let encrypt
which is an Acme issuer uh people also
use Hashi cor Vault I've also seen
people use cloud flare in their
clusters the next thing I wanted to know
is also the SE manager seems to have a
lot of these third party dependencies
could this be an attack Vector because I
guess if the CT manager goes down then
the the trust is going to be severely
affected right so how how does one
combat against that so I think yes C
manager does rely on the issuers right
that that's how it requests certificates
and requests renewals that's part of
that life cycle management bit right so
your Ingress or service has some sort of
annotation that s manager knows and so
when it sees that pop up it goes out and
requests a certificate and does the
whole verification bit whether it's via
DNS record or via um an HTTP like
configuration file or something like
that and then uh you know Provisions
thater hands it off to creat a secret
with that uh that sear data in it and
gives it to the workload so in that the
only time it really needs to go outside
the cluster and talk to a third party is
during that initial certificate creation
and during renewal so I've actually seen
uh situations where there's been an
issue with Lessing uh it's been
very rare but it has happened but when
you think about what s manager is doing
it's not constantly like running and
updating or or anything like that like
so once your workload gets a certificate
it has a certificate and it has it for
90 days and like I said there's a 30-day
window when aert manager tries to renew
that CT so unless you have some
humongous issue where let en Crypt is
going to be down for 30 days you're
probably going to be it's not going to
be a big deal like I don't think I don't
think there's really a thing of C
manager going down and then affecting
the trust model similarly when we get
into talking about Linker D and that
East West that e East West security C
manager again really only manages the
trust anchor and the trust anchor is
like a CA so it's more long lived and
Linker D actually takes care of issuing
certificates for its own internal
components without going off cluster it
uses it internal CA so that's not going
to be affected by any sort of third
party being unavailable either so I
think there's not much to worry about
there okay yeah I think I was actually
more thinking because I think we had
there was this one case in 2011 or
something about this company called dig
not I mean I could get the wrong name
maybe not right but that had again it
was a certificate issuing company and I
think they had a breach or something and
then entally all the certificates that
were given out were basically invalid
right so then so then I was I was sort
of thinking that worst case scenario
because now the CT manager is like the
central of our zero trust so if what
would happen in that case is sort of the
worst case scenario that I was thinking
yeah but that's not that's not specific
to se manager right it's it's anything
that uses yeah any certificate Authority
okay okay now we can talk a little bit
about Linker D which is the next open
source project uh and that talks about
the service meshes how is this different
from the other service meshes we've done
a bunch of shows on service meeses for
uh the listeners I think you can take a
look at Episode 600 but the question
here I wanted to know is from you CV is
like how is Linker different from the
other service meses that are out there I
think one of the main differences that
Linker likes to point out is that it's
written in Rust and that uses his own
custombuilt proxy not not Envoy which is
a a standard that you'll find in a lot
of Ingress Solutions and so you know I
think the folks linkerd will tell you
that it's uh that's part of what makes
it so fast also that it's super simple
in its configuration and does a lot of
stuff out of the box that enables you to
just get going with at least basic
configurations like Mutual TLS so yeah I
think that's probably the biggest
difference
okay and we talked a little bit about
you know checking access every time in
zero trust uh how does that work with
linky I think you talk about the east
west traffic being supported by mtls can
you talk a little bit about that yeah
so when we talk about it checking every
access every time it's essentially tied
into into identity so the kubernetes
service kubernetes service accounts are
uh the base identity that's used Behind
these uh certificates so the Linker D um
proxy agent which is a a sidecar that
runs along uh side your containers in
your pod it's responsible for requesting
the certificate and then verifying the
certificate data and verifying the
identity of the workload submitting the
certificate against the identity issuer
which is another component that link
installs inside your cluster so it's
constantly when you're doing Mutual TLS
it's not only encrypting the traffic but
it's also using the ca that it creates
to verify that that the entity on the
certificate really has permission to use
that certificate that really brings that
ties that trust angle a lot with this
access pattern when you're talking a
little bit about the access pattern I
also want to talk about the thing that
you spoke a little bit before that
usually in kubernetes most of the
are allowed to talk to each other uh so
what happens with Linker D is that
something that we have like is there a
possibility of having a default deny or
is is that there in the
configuration yes yeah absolutely so you
can I believe you can
annotate a name space with a deny and
then that will deny all traffic and then
you'll have to like go in and explicitly
say who's allowed to talk to to who okay
so then that follows our principles of
leaves privileges now but I'm assuming
then it's possible to add like a level
of
permissions or some sort of an ARB back
over that okay is that something that
yeah there's um I can't remember the
exact name of the object it's like mtls
authentication policy I think there are
three pieces that go along with that
there's like a a server piece that
identifies the server that you want to
access there's a mtls authentication
object that then sort of maps um who's
allowed to talk to that server ports
they're allowed to talk on yeah so there
are like other components you can deploy
to your cluster in order to start
controlling traffic between workloads
and restrict workloads based on the
service that it's going to or Port
that's trying to talk to also the path I
think you can restrict so you can say
the service a can talk to service B but
it can only go it can only talk to
service B on a specific path and a
specific Port so you can get very
granular with it I believe okay so then
yeah that that really then brings in the
concept of lease privileges uh with
Linker d right because you can specify
the path the port and then like you said
who's allowed to talk to it yeah so the
authentication because there's a default
deny and I guess the other concept is
now what if something bad happens to one
of the name spaces or is it possible
that you know you can lock something
down yeah so I think that is that
default deny policy that you can apply
to name spaces okay okay so the when
you're monitoring and you see
something's not going well you can
actually go and sort of configure the
link or D configuration to deny yes so
you can you can either be specific and
use one of those like depending on how
much of a panic you're in right you can
you can just go ahead and say nothing
can talk to anything in this name space
and that will solve that nothing will be
able to talk to it or you can go in and
change one of those objects that I was
talking about earlier the server the
mtls authentication Service is uh the
other one I was trying to remember and
uh authorization policy those three go
together to um put fine grain access
permissions between workloads so you can
go and change those or you can just shut
off the lights and uh apply an
annotation to a namespace pretty quickly
okay I wanted to talk a little bit about
identities also right what are the
different types of identities that you
would uh see in a reference architecture
so I guess if it's nor South you'll see
user identities other things that you
can talk
about yeah yeah I mean you do depending
on what you have in your environment so
again like what you need to provision
the sort of reference architecture you
need to create and the policies you need
to create really depends on what your
environment is like so if you have
devices or you have devices can be part
of that um how they're allowed to access
your network that's a I feel like that
is a component of identity but I think
in general we're talking specifically
about like you said users and we're
talking about
workloads and so when we talk about
users we're talking about controlling
those with arbac and using like a third
I want to say a third party but an
external authentication Service along
with that so I IM I am is a a very
common way to uh authenticate users to
your environment and then you use rbec
to do the authorization piece like what
are they allowed to do that's one level
of identity and that also ties into
workload identity so that's another
factor and that is what it sounds like
it's it's essentially your workloads
taking on you know having a Persona they
have um an identity that with it also
has the ability to be authenticated
outside the cluster using I am again and
then also having arbc policies that
control what those workloads can do so
you know one of the things I mentioned
earlier is um because of the decoupled
nature of Emissary you know your Ingress
isn't just one object that sits in the
same Nays space as your workload um and
then potentially your developers have
complete access to configuring that
however they want creating whatever path
they want going to whatever service so
you can imagine if you have some sort of
breach and some thing is in your network
it can alter an Ingress and be like okay
everybody you know everybody end this is
all open or whatever or create some
opening for themselves with the way the
Emissary does it it creates its own
there's a separate host object so the
host object can sit somewhere else and
then we can use that parts of that
identity piece
to protect that host object and say that
only people who belong to this group the
systems operator group or whatever have
access to that Nam space or within that
Nam space only this group has the
ability to edit that host configuration
or what we' most likely do is even take
that out of the realm of being um
necessarily just about specific people
en roles but tie that into our cicd
environment take that out and make it
like a non-human uh identity that uh
controls those things so there are
multiple identities that come into play
there's the user identity there's
workload identity and then apart from
that you have the authentication Service
that you can apply on on the host and
then apart from that you can also have
an authorization and certain rules which
you can configure and then of course
you've got all your your Ingress uh
controls as well so at the network layer
that that is also there so it's almost
like a very layered approach so the
identity you can slap on a lot and then
that ties in well with our least
privileges so yeah I think that's quite
I think it answers my question and
hopefully for the listeners as well yeah
that's what we call defense in death so
I I I think now it would be a good time
to talk a little bit about policy
enforcement which we talked about as one
of the tenants of zero trust uh networks
uh I think there was a NSA hard ing
guidelines for kubernetes and if I look
at that it's huge a lot of stuff to do
yes yeah so how do teams uh Implement
things like that so is um did the
[Laughter]
whole I kid I kid but
yes it's huge but I I was wondering if
the uh you know this the the whole
concept of the of Polaris and open
source projects like that came out of
the fact that this would be an easy way
like a cookbook to implement some of
those
guidelines yeah the NSA hardening
guidelines are great and they are super
detailed and they outline a lot of very
a lot of so this I can this is my my
strong subject here since this is
Polaris we're GNA well we haven't you
haven't said the name but yeah yeah
Polaris but Polaris which we're going to
talk about in relation to policy is a a
Fair Winds project and yeah so those
hardening guidelines are super detailed
very useful they are a lot of the
guidelines that we at Fairwinds have
followed before you know this even
became a thing like setting CP request
limits and and things like that in terms
of how teams Implement that is hard
because there's a lot of U material
there and teams would normally have to
manually check for these things across
like all their workloads or systems and
then configure them I figure out how to
configure them and test and make sure
it's not going to break everything and
then it's not a one-time thing it has to
be an ongoing process because every new
application every new workload that you
deploy to your cluster has the ability
to like violate one of those best
practices
you know doing all that manually is a
real it's a real pain and I think it
oftentimes what you see is teams will go
in with the intention of uh implementing
these these um guidelines hardening
their systems it takes a long time to do
and by the time they get to the end
they're like okay we're done but by that
time a bunch of other workloads have
been deployed to the cluster and they
rarely go back and start all over again
they rarely do the cycle so implementing
that is is difficult a like without some
help okay so I guess the so from for
Polaris which is the open source policy
engine from Fairwinds what is it why
should one choose Polaris over there are
a lot of other policy engines like Opa
keru uh I think so maybe you could just
break it down for someone like me so
Polaris is an open policy engine like I
said uh that was is open open source uh
developed by
Fairwinds and it comes with a bunch of
predefined policies that are based off
those NSA guidelines plus you have the
ability to create your own and it is a
tool is not like the tool I'm not going
to say it's the only tool right because
as you mentioned there are lots of other
open source uh there also other policy
engin out there but it is a tool that
you could use when you ask how to teams
Implement those guidelines to is a a a
good way to do that right because it's
sort of a three- tiered approach you
know you run it manually to
determine what things are in violation
of the policies that you want so there's
a CLI component that you can run in a
dashboard that you can look at you fix
all those things up and then in order to
maintain adherence to those guidelines
you can run Polaris either in your cicd
pipeline uh so that it blocks it shifts
left and prevents anything from getting
into your cluster in the first place
that would uh violate one of those
guidelines and you can run it as an
emission controller so it will reject or
at least warn about any workloads or um
objects in your cluster that violate
those guidelines as well so that is you
know when we talk about how to teams
Implement those guidelines using
something like that like a policy engine
is the way to go now why Polaris over
Opa or kerno I mean I'm biased obviously
but I think that the the preconfigured
policies that Polaris comes with are
really a big deal because there's a lot
of stuff that just right out of the box
Mak sense and again is best practice
because it's based on those that NSA
hardening document so it can be it can
make it easier and faster to get up and
running with some Basics and then you
can write your own policies and those
policies can be written using Json
schema which is much easier to rock in
my opinion than uh Opa because then
you're writing Rego policies and Rego
policies can be they can be a little um
difficult to get right so and U there's
also this other concept here which you
call
B which is bring your own checks can you
talk a little bit about that yeah so
that's more about the the fact that you
can write your own policies so for
example when we talk in the context of
the zero trust reference architecture
that we've been alluding to during this
talk there are objects that are not
natively part of a kubernetes cluster
and so the checks that we have in place
don't take those into consideration
right it' be impossible to write checks
against every possible crd that's out
there so one of the things that you
might want to do for example is you
might want to check if you if you're
using link your D and uh you might want
to check that every workload in your
cluster is part of the service mesh
right you don't want something sitting
outside of it so you can write a policy
in Polaris that checks for the existence
of like you know the The annotation
that's used to add a workload to the
service mesh you can check to make sure
that you know every every workload has a
server object
that along with the mtls authentication
policy object etc etc so you can you
know tweak Polaris to check very
specific things that are part of like
the kubernetes native API which I think
is super
helpful okay I also wanted to ask you in
terms of you you're able to point out
like policy violations but is there a
way that any of these agents can also
fix issues no not at the moment it is
not a um so it's it's not um active in
that way so it will print out the issue
it'll it can print it the standard out
if you're running the CLI obviously the
dashboard will show you uh and if you're
running the admission controller when it
rejects your workload it will print that
out to standard out as well okay it just
reports on it it's non yeah
nonintrusive okay okay and uh you talked
a little bit about this dashboard right
for viewing these violations so does
that come out of the box so if you
install Polaris you'll also get the Das
board mhm yeah corre okay okay and so
that I guess it gives you an overview of
all the passing checks or the violations
and things like yeah it it breaks it
down by namespace and So within each
namespace it'll show you the workload
and then under the workload it'll show
you uh which policies have been violated
you can set also uh severity of these
policies as well so that helps control
whether or not a violation means you
can't deploy it to the cluster at all or
whether it's just going to give you like
a heads up that that's a thing so you
know it doesn't have to be all Breaking
or or anything like that so I think
we've covered a bit about Polaris and I
think I I like to wrap the show with
some other questions that I have just a
couple of questions one is um are there
any challenges that you have seen with
real teams real examples on you know
implementing this reference architecture
I think in general it's just you know
the human element of being frustrated by
restrictions especially if you're not
used to them so you have to really get
Buy in from uh your teams and you also
have to balance what works for them in
terms of their velocity and and keeping
your environment secure so you don't
want to come in and like throw in a
bunch of policies all of a sudden and
then just be like there you go because
that's going to that's going to cause
friction and then people will always
look for ways around the policies that
you put in place the communication piece
is super important because you don't
want to slow down velocity and progress
for your Dev teams because they're uh
there's a lot because there are a lot of
roadblocks in their way okay and what's
the future of zero trust what are the
other new areas of development that you
see in this reference architecture space
for kubernetes I mean I really just see
the continuing adoption and uh and
deeper integration across Ross the the
existing pillars right so we've
identified these pillars and I was
talking about how you can uh Implement
something in your cluster and then think
yay I'm done but generally there's a a a
path in fact there's a maturity model I
think that um has been released that
talks about each level of maturity
across all those pillars right so I
think just helping people move move up
that maturity model and that means like
integrating zero trust more deeply into
each of those pillars using things like
the automation piece uh using things
like the observability and analytics
piece I think is really going to be
where the focus is going forward so
focusing on how to progress progress
from like the Standard Security
implementation to the advanced one okay
so more adoption rather than new things
coming across and maturity
okay exactly exactly and what about the
piece on you know this automatic fixing
and selfhealing what what do you think
about that like the ones where you talk
about the like the policy violations if
it it prints it out but what do you
think about automatic fixing is that
something that should be done or maybe
uh it could actually make things go bad
it could go either way but I think in
general yeah I think there's a push
towards having some just like kubernetes
yourself right having some self-healing
components so you know
setting things like um and I'm going
back to like resources right if your
policy is every workload has to have a
CPU and memory requests and limits set
then do you reject a workload because it
doesn't have it and have the message go
back to the developer I need to you need
to put that in there or do you have uh a
default that says if that's missing just
just put that in there I think it
depends I think that it could be um by
self-healing in that respect can be
great depending on what it is you're
healing right so what it is what the
policy is maybe not with resources I
think because resources are so variable
and you don't want to have something put
in like there's no way to really have a
good Baseline uh default resource
template across all workloads right but
you could have something TOA like you're
going to set uh the user to non rout
right or you're going
to gosh I don't know any number of other
things you're going to do link or D
inject uh you're going to add that
annotation to the workloads like if it
doesn't have it as opposed to rejecting
it just go ahead and putting it in there
things like that I think are are
absolutely great and I think those would
be great adoptions to have okay thank
you thank you for this and thanks for
coming on the show Stevie U what is the
best way people can reach you on the
cyberspace oh I'm on LinkedIn I think
it's just Stevie Caldwell I don't think
there's a there are actually a lot of us
but you know you you'll know me uh yeah
that's pretty much the best way okay so
I I'll add I'll find you on LinkedIn and
add it to the show notes and just wanted
to thank you for coming on the show and
I think demystifying zero trust Network
reference AR architecture so thanks for
this you're welcome thank you for having
me it's been a pleasure this is Priyanka
Ragan for software engineering radio
thanks for
listening thanks for listening to SC
radio an educational program brought to
you by It software magazine for more
about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website at se-
radio.net to provide feedback you can
comment on each episode on the website
or reach us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter
or through our slack Channel at seo.
slack.com you can also email us at team
e-r. this and all other episodes of SC
radio is licensed under Creative Commons
license
2.5 thanks for listening